Guide to the Archives of Irish America Pamphlet Collection AIA.047
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- General Collection, 1843-1992
  - Revolutionary Warfare. James Connolly. New Books Publications. Dublin (2 copies), 1968 (Box 2)
  - The Rights of Women in Ireland. Repsol Pamphlet No. 20., National Women's Committee. Sinn Fein. Dublin, 1975 (Box 2)
  - The Rise and Fall of Irish Anti-Semitism: The 1904 campaign by Pat Feeley and The Sinn Fein Tradition. Manus O'Riordan. Labour History Workshop, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Robert Emmet: An Address Delivered at an Emmett Commemoration in New York on March 9th, 1914. Patrick Pearse. Kilmainham Jail Historical Museum, 1975 (Box 2)
  - The RUC: The Black and Blue Book, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Separatist Socialist Republican. Liam McMillen. Repsol Pamphlet No. 21. Republican Education Deparment [Sinn Fein], Dublin, undated (Box 2)
  - Saor Eire: Indictment of Capitalism and Parliamentary Parties in Ireland. Fodhla Printing Company, Dublin, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Social and Economic Programme. Sinn Fein, undated (Box 2)
  - Songs and Ballads of '98. '98 Commemoration Association. [Wexford?], 1938 (Box 2)
  - Speech from the Dock: On the Occasion of his Trial under the Defence of the Realm Act, in the Dublin Police Court in June, 1915. F. Sheehy Skeffington. Skeffington Memorial Committee. New York, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Stepping Stones. Irish Book Bureau, Dublin, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - The Story of Irish Labour. J.M. MacDonnell. National Labour Press, Ltd. London, circa 1920 (Box 2)
  - The Story of Irish Labour. J.M. MacDonnell. Cork Workers Club Historical Reprints No. 10. Cork, Dec 1974 (Box 2)
  - The Story of the Irish Citizen Army. Sean O'Casey. Oriole Chapbooks. Oriole Editions. New York, undated (Box 2)
  - They are Innocent!: The Story of the Irish Republican Prisoners. Gerald O'Reilly. Connolly Commemoration Committee. New York, 1947 (Box 2)
  - They Shoot Children: The Use of Rubber and Plastic Bullets in the North of Ireland. Information on Ireland. London, 1982 (Box 2)
  - A Trinity of Martyrs: Terence MacSwiney, Cathal Brugha, Austin Stack. Anniversary Lectures Delivered at Sinn Fein Headquarters by Sceilg. John Joseph O'Kelly. Irish Book Bureau, Dublin, 1947 (Box 2)
  - The Truth About Ireland in the Great War: An Analysis of Admiral Sims' Unfair Attack on the Irish People. Irish National Bureau, Washington, D.C., 1919 (Box 2)
  - There's a Job to Do: A Statement of Policy. Northern Ireland Labour Party. Belfast, Mar 1952 (Box 2)
  - They Came in the Morning. Seamus O Tuathail, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - This is the Answer: Labour Keeps Faith. Northern Ireland Labour Party. Belfast, Apr 1949 (Box 2)
  - Tony O'Reilly's Last Game. Research Section. Department of Economic Afairs. Sinn Fein The Workers' Party. Repsol Publications. Dublin, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Torture Trial in Belfast. John Hostettler, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Towards the Socialist Republic. Outline Policies of Sinn Fein. Dublin, undated (Box 2)
  - Ulster: The Future. Frank McManus. Jan Press. New York, Jun 1972 (Box 2)
  - Undisguised Anglo-American Alliance. Celebration of "One Hundred Years of Peace" with England. A Skillfully [sic] Planned and Dangerous Attempt to Link the Two Nations Together - France and Germany, who Helped to Make this Country Free, to be Invited Only to Participate in English Festivities, and Russia, whose Action Foiled England's Plan to Break Up the Union, Wholly Ignored-Scheme to Anglicize the Schools-Wharton Barker's Emphatic Protest, 1911 (Box 2)
  - United States, Britain, Ireland: A Special Special Relationship. Leonard Brenner, circa 1972 (Box 2)
  - The U.S.S.R. Through Irish Eyes (Being the Report of the Irish F.O.S.R. Delegation, August, 1930). Friends of Soviet Russia. Dublin (Box 2)
  - The Wealth of the Cecils: Foundations of Political Power Stolen from English Taxpayers. Being Some Chapters from the Shame of the Peerage Hereto Unpublished in America. Henry William Fisher. Friends of Irish Freedom National Bureau of Information. Washington, D.C., Jul 1920 (Box 2)
  - The Woes of Ireland. Rev. A. M. Skelly, O. P. Seattle, WA, undated (Box 2)
  - The Workers Party: The Case for Devolved Government in Northern Ireland. Central Executive Committee. The Workers Party. Dublin and Belfast, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Workers' Party Wolfe Tone Commemoration Bodenstown. Oration: Cathal Goulding, Jun 1987 (Box 2)
  - The Writings of Bobby Sands 1954-1981. Irish Northern Aid. New York (Box 2)
  - Individual Leaflets, circa 1920s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Ernie O'Malley Pamphlet Collection, 1903-1924
  - The American Commission on Conditions in Ireland: Interim Report. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago, 1921 (Box 2)
  - An Smaointeori. Gaelic League of the State of New York, Nov 1919; Incscribed by Liam Mellows for Ernie O'Malley; inscribed by Liam Mellows to Ernie O'Malley (Box 2)
  - Background of the Irish Republic. Miss Mary MacSwiney. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago, 1920 (Box 2)
  - The Constructive Work of Dail Eireann No. 1. The National Police and Courts of Justice. Talbot Press, Limited. Dublin, 1921 (Box 2)
  - The Constructive Work of Dail Eireann No. 2. I. THe Department of Agriculture and the Land Settlement Commission; II. The Commission of Inquiry into the Resources and Industries of Ireland; III. The Department of Trade and Commerce. Talbot Press, Limited. Dublin, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Dail Eireann, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Damaging Evidence Against English Hypocrisy. Two Dates, 1882-1814. Egypt and Belgium. Berlin, 1915 (Box 2)
  - The Economics of Ireland and the Policy of the British Government. George W. Russell ("AE"). B.W. Huebsch, Inc. New York, 1920 (Box 2)
  - English Atrocities in Ireland. A Compilation of Facts from Court and Press Records. Katherine Hughes. Friends of Irish Freedom. New York, circa 1920 (Box 2)
  - Erin's Hope: The End and the Means. James Connolly. J.E.C. Donnelly. New York, circa 1914 (Box 2)
  - Facts About Ireland for Consideration of American Citizens: Sinn Fein Means "Ourselves Alone." The Plea of Overtaxation. The Delegates of the Protestant Churches of Ireland. Belfast, undated (Box 2)
  - The Foundation of the Republic of Ireland in the Vote of the People. Results of the General Election of December, 1918: a National Plebiscite held under British Law and British Supervision. Eamon de Valera (Box 2)
  - The Gaelic League and Politics. Dr. Dougland Hyde. Cahill and Co. Dublin, 1914 (Box 2)
  - The Gaelic State in the Past & Future or "The Crown of Nation." Darrell Figgis. Maunsel & Co., Ltd. Dublin, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Ghosts. P.H. Pearse. Whitely and Wright. Dublin, 1915 (Box 2)
  - Inner and Outer Ireland A.E. (George W. Russell). Talbot Press. Dublin (2 copies), 1921 (Box 2)
  - Inner and Outer Ireland A.E. (George W. Russell.) Irish Press and Publicity Bureau. San Francisco, circa 1921 (Box 2)
  - Ireland and the Empire at the Court of Conscience. A.E. (George W. Russell) The Talbot Press Limited. Dublin, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Ireland's Claim for Recognition as a Sovereign Independent State. Presented officially to the Government of the United States by Eamon De Valera, President of the Irish Republic. Irish Diplomatic Mission. Washington, D.C., 1920 (Box 2)
  - Ireland's Declaration of Independence. Padraig Pierce (fragment), undated (Box 2)
  - Ireland's Fight for Independence: Address of Miss Mary MacSwiney, February 7. All-American Bureau of Speakers for the Irish Republic. Chicago, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Ireland's Importance to the World. Lincoln Colcord, G.K. Chesterton The New Republic. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago (2 copies), 1921 (Box 2)
  - Irish Bulletin vol. 3, nos. 67, 68, 69, 70, 71, 72. The Irish Diplomatic Mission. Washington, D.C., 1921 (Box 2)
  - Irish Bulletin, vol. 4, nos. 36/37, 39, 45. Irish Diplomatic Mission. Washington, D.C., 1921 (Box 2)
  - Irish Councils for Irish Freedom. Results of the County and Rural Council Elections in Ireland in June, 1920, under the Proportional Representation System of Voting. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago (Box 2)
  - Irish Republican Army. Alice Stopford Green. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago, [1920] (Box 2)
  - Irish Socialist Republic. Holidays. Facts about Ireland for Consideration of American Citizens, How the Critics Received Robinson's Tristam, The Government of the Republic is the De Jure Government of Ireland. Propaganda Committee, Socialist Party of Ireland. Dublin, undated (Box 2)
  - Is there a Republic in Ireland? H.N. Brailsford. Reprinted from The London Nation. The Protestant Friends of Ireland. New York, 1919 (Box 2)
  - The Lessons of the Irish History and the Gospel of Irish Nationalism. Dealing with Ireland's Ancient Glory, English Rule in Ireland, the Establishment of the Republic, and the Betrayal fo the "Treaty." American Association for the Recognition of the Irish Republic. New York, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Magna Charta or The Great Charter of King John, Granted June 15, A.D. 1915. Old South Leaflets. No. 5. [London?], undated (Box 2)
  - The New Evangel Preached to Irish Toilers. State Monopoly versus Socialism. Socialist Party of Ireland. Dublin, undated (Box 2)
  - Prodigal Daughter: A Comedy in One Act. F. Sheehy Skeffington. The Co-Operative Press. New York, 1917 (Box 2)
  - The Recognised Irish Republic. Wm. J.M. A. Maloney, M.D. New York, circa 1920 (Box 2)
  - Report on the Irish Situation. Lieutenant-General Sir Henry Laswon, K.C.B. Caledonian Press. London, 1920 (Box 2)
  - Republican Courts in Ireland. W.H. Brayden. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago, 1920 (Box 2)
  - The Rights of Ireland and The Faith of Felon, 1848. James Fintan Lawlor. 1848. Socialist Party of Ireland. Dublin, circa 1914 (Box 2)
  - The Royal Visit. Irish Socialist Republican Party. Dublin (2 copies), 1903 (Box 2)
  - The Struggle of the Irish People. Address to the Congress of the United States. Government Printing Office. Washington, D.C., 1921 (Box 2)
  - Torture and Terror: 1. The Torture of Kevin Berry 2. The Torture of Thomas Hales 3. Frightfulness in Thurles 4. The Burning of Balbriggan. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago, 1920 (Box 2)
  - What's Wrong with Ireland? John Hampden Bright. Benjamin Franklin Bureau. Chicago, 1920 (Box 2)